Well, the holographic principles suggest that it's possible...
Les principes holographiques démontrent qu'il est possible
...that our lives are reallyjust acting out a painting...
que nos vies ne soient qu'un tableau vivant
...on the largest canvas in the universe.
sur la plus grande toile de l'univers.
-What? -Sometimes I forget how smart you are. Heh.
- Quoi ? - Parfois, j‘oublie comme tu es intelligent.
What are you doing?
Que fais-tu ?
Take off your clothes.
Déshabille-toi.
-What? Here? Now? -You got a problem with that?
- Tout de suite ? - Ça te dérange ?
-We did it in there. -Yeah, we did.
- On l‘a fait. - Oui.
MAN: Big Bang Theory season six cast interviews.
Interview des acteurs de Big Bang Theory Saison 6
Count and mark.
Marque.
I've always said this when they ask about Leonard and Penny.
Pour la relation entre Leonard et Penny,
It's mirrored a real relationship, it is a little up and down.
c‘est une vraie relation avec ses problèmes.
They've broken up, they're best friends...
Ils ont rompu, ils sont proches.
...and, you know, they've dated, and they've dated other people.
Ils étaient ensemble, ils sont allés voir ailleurs,
Their friends are each other's friends, and it's a complicated relationship.
ils ont des amis communs. Leur relation est compliquée.
And there's deep, true love for each other, you know.
Ils s'aiment profondément.
Good morning, sunshine.
Bonjour, mon soleil.
Leonard...
Leonard,
...it's 8 am.
il est8 h.
It's like the middle of the night.
C‘est le milieu dela nuit.
I like that it hasn't been this fairy tale story.
J'aime que ce ne soit pas un conte de fées.
I feel like they're in a good place now. I'm afraid to say that out loud.
Ils sont bien maintenant, mais j'ai peur de dire ça.
Don't say that. What is wrong with you?
Ne dis pas ça.
We'll read the script for the last episode of the season tomorrow...
On lira le scénario du dernier épisode dela saison,
-Look, there's something I need to tell you. -Just say it.
- Il faut que je te dise quelque chose. - Dis—le.
-Okay. Here goes. -Mm-hm.
Bien. Voilà.
You slept with him?
Tu as couché avec lui ?
I laugh because I still don't know, every script I get, if we're together or not.
Je ris parce que je ne sais jamais s‘ils sont ensemble ou pas.
-lt's kept me on my toes. -Sometimes it's hard to tell.
- Ça me tient en haleine. - C‘est dur a dire.
CUOCO: Yeah.
Oui.
Even though their relationship is on and off, they've been in a relationship for a long time.
Malgré les hauts et les bas, leur relation dure depuis longtemps.
I think it's matured the show as a whole.
Ça apporte de la maturité àla série.
Definitely matured, yeah.
Oui.
There are much more adult issues.
Il y a plus de problèmes d'adultes.
I don't mean that in a risqué way, whatsoever.
Pas au niveau sexuel.
I'm here to support my man, just like you.
Je Viens soutenir mon homme comme toi.
What are you going to do?
Que vas-tu faire ?
The characters are growing up.
Les personnages mûrissent.
They're growing up and it's just kind of a natural thing.
C‘est naturel.
Although, I still never saw all these characters in these deep relationships.
Je ne les avais jamais imaginés dans des relations fortes.
But itjust happened naturally...
Mais c‘est arrivé naturellement.
...and, you know, now there's so many fun things to play with that.
Il y a tellement de choses intéressantes ajouer.
It's just happened really beautifully.
Ça s‘est joliment développé.
-Hi, I'm Penny. -Alex.
- Salut, je suis Penny. - Alex.
-Do you work with Dr. Hofstadter? -In a way.
- Une collaboratrice ? - En quelque sorte.
We've kind of been involved in a five-year experiment.
Nous menons une expérience depuis cinq ans.
Well, you're lucky, he seems very talented. I'm sure a lot of people wanna work with him.
Quelle chance ! Beaucoup de gens veulent travailler avec lui.
Oh, well, a lot of people can't, so....
Peu de gens le peuvent...
Penny got a little jealous.
Penny était un peu jalouse.
I think it's important for Leonard to learn his street value once in a while...
C‘est important pour Leonard de constater sa valeur
...out there on the market.
sur le marché.
I know she hit on you and I know you liked it.
Tu as aimé qu'elle te drague.
What?
Quoi ?
I like that they made it Penny getting jealous this time, you know.
J'aime le fait que Penny soitjalouse cette fois.
Because Leonard's usually the one.
C‘est souvent Leonard.
-Gets very threatened. -Yes.
- Il se sent menacé. - Oui.
I don't care about Alex.
Je me fiche d‘Alex.
Fine, I care.
Ce n‘est pas vrai.
Okay, I hate that bitch.
Je déteste cette pouffiasse.
He kind of-- He had a little bit of an ego about it.
Il était un peu fier.
-You were a little too excited. -Which in the end was probably healthy...
- Tu étais un peu trop satisfait. - Ce qui était sain
...to bring back into our relationship.
pour notre relation.
Obviously, I have some commitment issues.
Il est évident quej'ai peur de m'engager.
Glaringly obvious. Go on.
Ça crève les yeux. Continue.
As long as things keep going great, you'll keep asking me to marry you...
Tant que ça ira, tu me demanderas de t'épouser,
...and eventually, I'm gonna end up saying yes.
etje vais ﬁnir par dire oui.
Then we're gonna be married forever and the whole thing just freaks me out.
Nous serons mariés pour la vie, et ça me fait peur.
First of all, it's one of my favorite Leonard lines ever, that:
C‘est l‘une de mes répliques préférées :
CUOCO & GALECKI: "I knowl propose a lot."
”Je sais que je t'ai déjà demandé de nombreuses fois."
So he says, "I'm not gonna propose." She goes, "Are you breaking up with me?"
Il dit : ”Je vais arréter." Elle dit : "Tu veux rompre ?"
It's like saying, "Are you calling me fat?"
Autant lui dire: "Tu me trouves grosse ?"
His solution was to say, "I'm not gonna ask.
Sa solution est de dire : ”Je vais mettre mon désir de côté
You tell me when you're ready."
et t'attendre."
Which I thought was really beautiful.
C‘était très beau.
It's all on you.
Ce sera ta décision.
I gotta tell you, when the time comes, I want the whole nine yards.
Mais le moment venu, tu as intérêt à m‘épater.
I want you down on one knee, flowers. I wanna be swept off my feet.
A genoux, avec des fleurs, et tout le tralala.
Okay.
D‘accord.
GALECKI: I loved that scene. CUOCO: I did too. It's so cute.
- J'ai adoré cette scène. - Elle était adorable.
That's unconditional love. That's selflessness, you know.
C‘est l‘amour sans condition.
You guys are like family to me, you know that, right?
Vous êtes comme une famille pour moi.
-That's great. Get out. -What? Why?
- Super. Sors. - Pourquoi ?
Penny and l have some issues we need to talk about.
Penny et moi avons des problèmes à régler.
Oh, pish on your issues.
Au diable vos problèmes !
After everything you've been through...
Aprés toutes ces épreuves,
...you get to look into each other's eyes and say "I love you."
vous pouvez vous regardez dans les yeux et proclamer votre amour.
And that's beautiful.
Et ça, c‘est beau.
Actually, to this day, she's never really said it.
En fait, elle l‘a encore jamais dit.
Oh, Penny, that's ridiculous.
Voyons, Penny, c‘est ridicule !
Well, in the episode where Penny drops the L bomb...
Dans l‘épisode dans lequel Penny largue la bombe A,
GALECKI: Mm-hm. Mm-hm. -...the "I love you"...
lui dit : ”Je t'aime",
...it's a very special scene and it comes out of nowhere.
c‘est une scène très spéciale. Ça sort de nulle part.
It comes out of her frustration...
Ça Vient de sa frustration
-...since you keep being so needy. -True.
- puisque tu manques d‘affection. - C‘est vrai.
Why do you always do this?
Pourquoi tu fais ça ?
Listen to me, you're the one I'm with.
C‘est avec toi que je suis.
You knowl love you.
Tu sais que je t‘aime.
So will you please relax because you're driving me crazy.
Détends-toi, tu me rends folle.
ltjust comes flying out of her mouth.
Ça lui échappe.
She doesn't know that she said it. And it's a little bit of an elephant in the room.
Elle ne réalise pas quelle l‘a dit. C‘est un énorme non-dit.
But it's wonderful. I think she's always--
Mais c‘est formidable.
-She's always known that she loves him. -Yes, she just hasn't said the word.
- Elle a toujours su. - C‘estjuste qu'elle ne le disait pas.
She's a bit of a commitment-phobe.
Elle a peur de s'engager.
Remember first time you said it, she said, "Thank you."
Quand tu lui as dit, elle a répondu "merci".
Right. Oh, I remember.
Oui, je me souviens.
-That was a rough one. -Mm-hm.
C‘était d u r.
And you kept coming back.
Et tu revenais àla charge.
Leonard's a fighter.
Leonard est un battant.
-He's a fighter, man. -He doesn't give up.
- C'est un battant. - Il n'abandonnejamais.
GALECKI: He's got a stubborn heart.
Il est têtu.
That's the first time you ever said that you love me.
C'est la première fois que tu me le dis.
Yeah.
Oui.
Well, it's cool because we only did that in one take in front of the audience...
On n‘a fait qu‘une seule prise devant le public,
...and that was it.
et c‘est tout.
I looked at Johnny, I'm like, "Did that feel the same for you?"
J'ai regardé Johnny : “Ça t‘a fait pareil ?"
Like, I literally felt like I had become Penny at that moment. It sounds so corny.
J‘avais l'impression d‘être Penny. Ça fait tellement sentimental.
I felt like ljust became Penny. I didn't even see an audience.
Je ne voyais même plus le public.
-There was no one but Leonard and Penny. -Everything and everyone kind of fell away.
- Il n'y avait que Leonard et Penny. - Tout avait disparu.
It felt like one of the most real moments...
C‘était l'un des moments les plus
-...like, I've ever had. -Yeah.
- authentiques. - Oui.
You're about to make me cry...
Tu vas me faire pleurer,
...and we both know ifl start crying, you're gonna start crying.
et si je commence, tu vas pleurer aussi.
-You're right, you should go. -All right.
- Tu as raison. Tu devrais y aller. - Oui.
We just were totally in Leonard and Penny world.
On était dans leur monde.
l was no one else but her at that moment. It was strange.
J‘étais Penny a ce moment. C‘était étrange.
It did. It felt like we were the only two people in the room. That's exactly--
Je croyais qu'on était seuls.
That's what you strive for on stage.
C'est ce qu'on recherche.
But especially with all of this, all this technical--
Surtout avec toute cette technique...
I mean, 500 people in the room, it's really hard to achieve that.
Devant 500 personnes, c‘est difficile d'y parvenir.
So, yeah, we did it once and never looked back.
On l‘a fait une fois, et on est allés de l'avant.
I love you.
Je t‘aime.
I love you too.
Je t'aime aussi.
I think we'd both like to see them end up together. I mean, I think--
On aimerait les voir ensemble.
-Yes. -Boy.
-Oui. - Bon sang!
That would be tragic after all they've been through.
Ce serait tragique après ce qu‘ils ont vécu.
I would cry like it was my own breakup.
Je pleurerais comme pour moi.
-Yeah. -I don't think I could handle it.
- Oui. - Je ne pourrais pas.
Whatever path these two choose, I want them to end up together.
Je veux qu‘ils finissent ensemble.
GALECKI: Yeah. -I want them to end up married, I really do.
- Oui. - Je veux qu‘ils se marient.
That's like my dream for these characters.
C'est mon rêve pour eux.
And lthink-- We deserve that because we haven't played it like that.
On le mérite parce qu'on ne l‘a pas joué comme ça.
Like, it's gone back and forth, we've broken up, we've--
On a rompu, il y a eu des allées et venues,
There's been so many things.
tant de choses.
-Yeah, the characters have earned it. -Yeah. It's not like, "Oh, that's typical."
- Les personnages le méritent. - Ce n‘est pas téléphoné.
If they walk away after all this empty-handed, good Lord.
S‘ils partaient les mains vides, mon Dieu !
I would cry my eyes out. I would die.
J'en pleurerais. Je mourrais.
-You'd cry through the entire episode. -Oh, I would die.
- Tu pleurerais tout l'épisode. - Je mourrais.
You don't know what it's like to feel completely frustrated.
Tu ne sais pas ce que c‘est d‘être frustré,
To have a desire build up within you...
quand on éprouve un désir
...and then be denied any opportunity for release.
qu'on ne peut pas exprimer.
Yeah, sounds like adrag.
Oui, ça doit craindre.
MAN: Sound speed.
Enregistrez.
Three camera, common mark.
Trois caméras, marque commune.
-I like your glasses. -Thank you.
- J'aime tes lunettes. - Merci.
I like them too. They wouldn't work for me.
Moi aussi. Elles ne m‘iraient pas.
Might work for me. Give me those glasses. Sorry.
A moi, si. Donne-les-moi. Pardon.
I've heard the comment several times this year...
On m‘a dit plusieurs fois qu'il y avait
And I guess that's true.
Je pense que c‘est vrai.
Amy, are you worried that us living together...
As-tu peur que Vivre ensemble
-No. -Yeah. Why would you?
- Non. -Oui, pourquoi ?
I think it's deeper in terms of learning about you.
Je pense que j'apprends ate connaître plus profondément.
-lt's like variations of the same. PARSONS: That's what I was gonna say.
- C'est une variation sur le même thème. - Oui.
I feel like the evolution has been-- There's not--
On n'évolue pas...
It's not this, it's this, with these little things in there.
Ce sont ces petites choses.
And that's been great, though...
C'est formidable
...because those are movements that are more true to life.
parce que ça ressemble àla vraie vie.
-They feel huge. BIALIK: Sure.
- Ces choses sont énormes. - Oui.
How was work today?
Comment était ta journée ? Tu as lu le travail de Kripke ?
I read his research...
J'ai lu son travail
...and it's leaps and bounds ahead of mine.
et il est bien supérieur au mien.
Sheldon, I wish there was something I could do to make you feel better.
J'aimerais pouvoir te remonter le moral.
May I offer you a consoling hug?
Un câlin consolatoire ?
What do we have to lose?
Qu'avons-nous a perdre ?
BIALIK: For me, I think--
Pour moi, je crois…
This is not hard to pull off because I adore Jim.
Et c‘est facile parce que j‘adore Jim.
I think that this Amy character is completely enamored with Sheldon...
Amy est éperdument amoureuse de Sheldon,
...and I think in the sweetest and most reasonable way.
tendrement et de façon très raisonnable.
lfeel like I'm being strangled by a boa constrictor.
C‘est comme être étouffé par un boa constricteur.
Why'd you stop?
Pourquoi tu t‘arrétes ?
You know, from all the kind of, like, funny comments about his sallow complexion...
D'après les blagues sur sa peau cireuse
-...and, you know, his hunched over-- -Watch it.
- et le fait qu'il soit courbé... - Attention !
Um, no, but I think for all his quirks, I think they're all forgivable.
Ses manies sont pardonnables.
Think about it, Sheldon. Your personality quirks...
Ces manies que les gens trouvent
...which others find abhorrent or rage-inducing...
abjectes ou exaspérantes, je les trouve irrésistibles.
-She doesn't have a lot of other options. -Well....
- Elle n‘a pas le choix. - Hé bien...
But still, there's something very attractive about their relationship.
Mais quelque chose est très séduisant dans leur relation.
In many ways, it is one of the most stable relationships on the show...
C‘est l‘une des relations les plus stables de la série,
...certainly until Wolowitz and Bernadette got married...
jusqu‘à ce que Wolowitz et Bernadette se marient,
...which I think solidifies things.
ce qui consolide les choses.
Well, who knows in today's society? No. Um, but....
Mais qui sait avec le monde d‘aujourd‘hui ?
There's a real understanding...
Ils se comprennent vraiment.
You know, when l have afeeling, I know it.
Je sais quand j'ai des sentiments.
And trains? Love them.
Et les trains ? J'adore.
Hand-holding? Not a fan.
Se tenir la main ? Je ne suis pas fan.
There's a very literal "I sacrifice this for you. I sacrifice this for you. l--"
Il dit littéralement: "Voilà ce que je sacrifie pour toi."
I mean, it's back and forth constantly with the two of them.
C‘est un échange entre eux.
It allows them a certain detachment from their feelings on the issues.
Ça leur permet de se détacher de leurs sentiments.
And when a bump comes up for this couple, they communicate and work it out.
Et quand un probléme arrive, ils communiquent et le résolvent.
-But we didn't finish. -Exactly.
- Mais on n‘a pas fini. - Exactement.
It's not the way anybody you've ever met communicates and works things out...
Ils ne communiquent pas comme les autres,
...but it works for them and they're both honest with each other.
mais ça marche pour eux, et ils sont honnêtes.
It's, I guess, the basis of a good long-term relationship, right?
C‘est comme ça que marche une relation de longue durée, non ?
I like Mayim too. I should throw that in.
J'aime beaucoup Mayim.
-l'm fond of you and so--l know. -It took you three minutes though.
- Je t'aime beaucoup... - Ça t‘a pris tu temps.
I do think that's definitely a part of our relationship.
Ça fait partie de notre relation.
I, as Jim, enjoy having Mayim in my life.
J'aime avoir Mayim dans ma vie.
-Sheldon, can I ask you a question? -Well, of course.
- Je peux te poser une question ? - Bien sûr.
Are you ever gonna sleep with Amy?
Vas-tu coucher avec Amy ?
All right, we're down the rabbit hole. What are you doing?
C‘est le moment de Vérité. Que fais-tu ?
I don't know another relationship that's been this long-term, stable...
Je n'ai pas vu d‘autre relation aussi longue, stable
...and intimate without being consummated.
et intime sans sexe.
-I think it's really kind of sweet and amazing. PARSONS Yeah.
- C‘est adorable et incroyable. - Oui.
And it's not the focal point of our plot lines or of our relationship.
Et ce n‘est pas le plus important dans l'histoire et la relation.
-It comes up. It comes up here and there. -Sex, it comes up.
- On en parle ici et la. - De sexe.
But it's kind of like, we're so far from that, like--
Mais on en est tellement loin.
-We clearly have a lot going besides doing it. -Exactly.
- On a autre chose a faire. - Exactement.
I know it doesn't seem like it to you...
Je sais que ce n‘est pas pareil pour toi,
...but, for me, what we have is extremely intimate.
mais pour moi, notre relation est extrêmement intime.
I guess I know that.
Je sais.
It's just, like, part of me wants more.
Une partie de moi veut aller plus loin.
More?
Plus loin ?
I mean, look at us, it's only been three years. Here we are in bed together.
Ça ne fait que trois ans, et on est ensemble sur le lit.
BIALIK: And I think that's sweet.
C‘est mignon.
It doesn't have to be this catastrophic relationship...
On n‘est pas obligés d‘être au bord de la catastrophe...
-Right. -...or pinnacle that we're balancing on.
- Oui. - dans un équilibre précaire.
I think it's-- I don't know. Young kids today could learn a thing or two.
Les jeunes pourraient s‘inspirer.
Hello, who are you?
Qui êtes-vous ?
I'm Alex, Dr. Cooper's assistant. Can I help you?
Alex, l‘assistante du Dr Cooper. Je peux vous aider ?
I'd like to speak to Sheldon.
Je peux parler a Sheldon.
I'm sorry. He's asked me to hold all calls.
Désolée, mais il ne veut pas être dérangé.
Well, tell him Amy called.
Dites—lui que c‘est Amy.
-Last name? -He knows my last name, I'm his girlfriend.
- Nom de famille ? - Il me connait, je suis sa copine.
We have a contract and everything. I'll send you a PDF.
Nous avons un contrat. Je vous enverrai le PDF.
There's kind of one-- Literally one episode where Amy was jealous of Alex and--
Il y a un épisode où Amy estjalouse d‘Alex.
Is that the one where I'm marking your office...
C‘est celui où je marque ton bureau
-...with my scent? PARSONS: With your body? Yes.
- avec mon odeur ? - Oui.
I think that's so indicative...
Ça montre comment
-...of how these relationships work. -Yeah.
- marchent ces relations. - Oui.
Like, Amy doesn't even know how to deal with potential drama and threat.
Amy ne sait pas comment gérer la menace.
-You're exactly right. -That was worth half an episode.
- C‘est ça. - Ça valait un demi-épisode.
-Yep. -Because you would have said:
-Oui. - Tu aurais dit:
-"What would I do with her?" -Right.
Que ferais-je avec elle ?
-The conversation would have been over.
- La discussion aurait été terminée. - Oui.
-Hello. -Happy Valentine's Day.
- Bonjour. - Joyeuse Saint Valentin.
Okay.
Ouais.
As you know, I had planned a traditional evening of romance and gifts.
Comme tu le sais, j‘avais prévu une soirée romantique et des cadeaux.
Yes, and as you know, I planned to pretend to enjoy it.
Et comme tu le sais, j'allais faire semblant de m‘amuser.
PARSONS: What did I give you at first? -Well, the table reading had us kissing.
- Qu‘est—ce que je te donnais ? - Tu devais m'embrasser.
-Oh, okay, we had a kiss. -Right.
-Oui, un baiser. -Oui.
-Got rid of that. We never rehearsed that. -Nope.
- On s‘est débarrassé de ça. - Oui.
-We came back the next day, it was gone. -Done.
- Le jour suivant le baiser avait disparu. - Fini.
They changed it a couple times but it ended up...
Ils l‘ont réécrit, et ça a fini par être
-...being so sweet. -I loved it.
- si tendre. - Super.
I came up with an even better way to celebrate Valentine's Day:
J'ai trouvé une meilleure Saint Valentin : ne faisons rien.
We stay here and watch one of your beloved Star War, Trek things
On reste àla maison pour regarder tes machins Star War Trek.
-Really? -Well, that's what you'd love, isn't it?
- Vraiment ? - C‘est ce que tu aimes, non ?
More than anything.
Plus que tout.
Well, then that's what we're gonna do.
Alors, c‘est ce qu'on va faire.
-You call off the whole evening, which-- -Right.
- Tu annules tout. -Oui.
Because it will please me.
Pour me faire plaisir.
And I've given you one of the nearest and dearest things to my heart.
Je te donne ce que j'ai de plus cher.
-What's this? -Read it.
- Qu‘est—ce que c‘est ? - Lis—le.
In case of emergency, please contact Amy Farrah Fowler.
En cas d'urgence, contacter Amy Farrah Fowler.
And there's my phone number.
Et il y a mon numéro de téléphone.
PARSONS: This is why I don't wanna say he's not romantic at all because--
Je ne veux pas dire qu'il n‘est pas romantique...
Does he know romance? Yes.
Connaît-il la romance ? Oui.
He knows what will get her.
Il sait ce qui va la faire fondre.
I just want you to get better as soon as possible.
Je veux me rétablir au plus Vite.
I still have to put a cold rag on your head...
Je dois rafraîchir ton front, chanter et étaler du Vicks VapoRub sur ta poitrine.
You wanna rub something on my chest?
Tu veux étaler quelque chose sur ma poitrine ?
Yes.
Oui.
All over it.
Sur toute ta poitrine.
BIALIK: That was a wicked episode for Amy.
C‘est un épisode super pour Amy.
That was definitely the most relationship-y thing she's done...
Elie n‘estjamais allée aussi loin dans les aspects
...in terms of some of those darker, you know, aspects of relationships.
plus sombres d‘une relation.
Here's the deal. I don't need your medicine. I'm not sick.
Il me faut tes médicaments. Je ne suis pas malade.
-So you've just been lying? -See the stuff in my nose? Rubber cement.
- Tu as menti ? -J'ai mis du mastique dans mon nez.
I don't mean to be judgy, but this is the kind of thing lunatics do.
Je ne veux pas te juger, mais c‘est un truc de malade mental.
-But it was so-- -But the motive was--
- Mais c‘était si... - Mais le but...
-You can say it. -The motivation was so pure.
- Dis—le. - C‘était pur.
That was so loving, you know?
C‘était si affectueux.
-She wanted to be with him. -Yes.
- Elle voulait... - Oui.
-She wanted to be touched... -It worked.
- être avec lui… - Ça a marché.
...and dealt with by him in a way that, under normal circumstances...
et qu'il s'occupe d'elle
...he would only do if she was in peril in some sort of way.
comme il le ferait seulement si elle était en danger.
BIALIK: Well, you have to meet him where he's at.
Elle a dû s'adapter.
And lthink, like, that's a lesson we all could learn, right?
C‘est une leçon pour nous tous.
You have to meet people where they're at.
Il faut savoir s'adapter.
Now, you may notice some tingling.
Ça va picoter.
Oh, I'm counting on it.
J'en suis sûre.
Again, this is where our relationship works, right?
C‘est la que notre relation marche.
-You play to the other person's sense... PARSONS: Yeah.
- On joue avec... - Oui.
...ofjustness and rightness...
le sens du devoir de l‘autre
...I guess for as much benefit, you know, personal benefit...
pour obtenir
-...and pleasure as you can. -Sure.
- le plus de plaisir. - Oui.
It hurts that you would lie to me, Amy.
Ça me blesse que tu puisses me mentir.
I thought our relationship was based on trust...
Notre relation était basée sur la confiance
...and a mutual admiration that skews in my favor.
et notre admiration mutuelle qui penche en ma faveur.
Another great example of us communicating very clearly.
C‘est un exemple de notre talent de communication.
-Absolutely. -Sheldon's saying, "That's not okay.
- Oui. - Sheldon dit : "C‘est inacceptable,
-We need to do something about it." -Yup.
-qu'il faut agir." -Oui.
-You gotta be punished. -And Amy's saying, "Okay. Oh, okay."
- Tu dois être punie. - Amy est d‘accord.
-There it was. Nothing we need to repeat. -It was Sheldon's suggestion to spank you.
- Il n'y avait rien à répéter. - Sheldon suggère de te fesser.
BIALIK: I know. -I don't want to...
Je sais.
...but it looks like I have no choice.
Je ne veux pas, maisje n'ai pas le choix.
Oh, my.
Mon Dieu.
I don't believe Sheldon understands why he wants-slash-needs Amy in his life.
Sheldon ne comprend pas pourquoi il a besoin d'Amy.
I think hejust knows that it's better to have her...
Il saitjuste qu'il préfère l‘avoir
-...than to not have her around. -Yep.
-que non. -Oui.
And I will say, because we enjoy working together so much...
Et parce qu'on aime travailler ensemble,
...and because it has brought such joy in the acting of the scenes together...
et que ça a apporté tellement de joie à nos scènes,
...I would really hope that they not stop this relationship...
j'espère qu‘ils ne vont pas interrompre cette relation,
...have it go on some sort of hiatus or whatever.
faire une pause.
I don't understand how that would happen...
Je ne sais pas comment ça pourrait arriver, mais ils nous ont déjà surpris.
-Don't go suggesting it. -Oh, God. No, I mean--
- Ne leur donne pas d'idées. - Oh, non.
I think we need a "final scene of Grease" scene...
On a besoin d‘une scène àla Grease
-...that's some important fantasy. -What does that mean?
- trés fantasmatique. - Que veux-tu dire ?
I wanna wear, like, sexy black leggings and heels with curly hair.
Je veux porter des leggings noirs, des talons et une permanente.
-No. She has different desires than I do. -Like a big ugly duckling reveal.
- Nous n‘avons pas les mêmes valeurs. - Comme la fin du vilain petit canard.
Saturday night? But I've been working late all week.
J‘ai travaillé toute la semaine.
That was gonna be our night.
C‘est notre soirée.
But I have to go. If I'm not there, then everyone will blame you.
Je dois y aller. Sinon, ils vont t'en vouloir.
They'll be all, "Bernadette ruined everything. She's the worst."
Ils diront : ”Bernadette a tout gâché, elle est nulle."
So you see? I have to play Dungeons & Dragons...
Tu vois ? Je dois allerjouer a Donjons & Dragons
...for the marriage.
pour notre mariage.
You're an idiot.
Tu es un idiot.
I'm your idiot.
Je suis ton idiot.
Forever.
Pour toute la Vie.
MAN: Three camera, common mark.
Trois caméras, clap commun.
-lt's like there's lots of cameras. -There's a lot of cameras.
- Beaucoup de caméras. - Oui, beaucoup.
Excuse me.
Excusez-moi.
RAUCH: You know, one thing I love about these writers...
Ce que j‘aime, c‘est que les auteurs
...is that they're always having us discover a new layer and I love getting their scripts...
nous font découvrir de nouvelles couches chez les personnages,
The course of the show I would say is vastly different.
La série évolue trés bien.
I don't think anyone would've suspected my character...
Personne n'aurait imaginé que
...would be the first to actually tie the knot.
je me marierais en premier.
Well, hello, Prince Charming.
Bonsoir, mon prince.
There's a lot more depth that we're getting into.
Il y a beaucoup de profondeur.
A lot more layers are being peeled away.
Avec plusieurs couches.
Sorry, we're late.
Pardon.
-Is everything okay? -Terrific. Couldn't be better.
- Tout va bien ? - Le mieux du monde.
Oh, bite me.
Arrête un peu.
HELBERG: I think it's a really cool facet of the show...
C‘est chouette pour la série
...that we can actually talk about marital issues.
de pouvoir parler de problèmes dans le mariage.
It opens up, I think, the story lines a tremendous amount.
Ça ouvre de nouvelles perspectives.
-You can'tjust throw everything in the closet. -Hey, you can tell me what to do...
- Ne mets pas tout dans le placard. - Tu me dis quoi faire
...or you can tell me how to do it.
ou comment faire.
But you can't do both. This isn't sex.
Pas les deux. Ce n‘est pas du sexe.
RAUCH: It's very true to life.
C‘est la vraie vie.
Just because you get married, it doesn't mean...
Le mariage ne signifie pas que vous savez tout de l'autre.
I think this season has been a lot about that for them.
Cette saison parle beaucoup d'eux.
Just, you know, figuring out financial issues and where they're gonna live together.
De leurs problèmes d‘argent, delà où ils vont vivre.
And lthinkjust getting to the heart of what a marriage is.
C‘est l‘essence même du mariage.
I've been working late every night.
Je travaille tard.
All I ask was that he clean the apartment and do one load of laundry.
Je lui demande juste de faire une lessive.
But did he do it? No. He just kept on playing that stupid game.
Mais non. Il préfére jouer a son jeu.
You like pushing buttons so much, try pushing them on the washing machine.
Si tu aimes appuyer sur des boutons, il y en a sur la machine a laver.
I said I'm sorry.
Je suis désolé.
Sorry doesn't clean my underpants, buddy.
Ça ne nettoiera pas mes culottes.
Bernadette is very forgiving, but also very strong.
Bernadette est indulgente et très forte.
Small but mighty.
Petite mais costaude.
I mean, it started a couple seasons ago.
Je suis la depuis quelques saisons.
But I think this season, well, she was kind of coming into her own marriage...
Dans cette saison, elle s'occupe de son mariage
...and realized that, you know, she's not the only Mrs. Wolowitz around...
et elle réalise qu'elle n‘est pas la seule Mme Wolowitz,
...and standing her ground and--
et elle tient bon…
Yeah. Bernadette really kind of whips him into shape in a loving way...
Bernadette Ie formate avec amour
Five thousand dollars for a couple of dolls?
5 000 $ pour deux poupées ?
Are you out of your mind?
Tu plaisantes ?
At any point, did it dawn on you to talk to me...
Tu n'as jamais pensé a me dire que tu allais dépenser autant.
It's kind of dawning on me now.
Je commence ale penser.
RAUCH: You know, when Howard spends his money on the printer...
Quand Howard achète l‘imprimante,
...it's something that in his old world wouldn't necessarily be something...
dans son ancien monde,
...that the whip would've been cracked on.
il ne se serait rien passé.
And I think that's also a part of navigating marriage...
C‘est ça aussi le mariage,
...and figuring out what your shared finances...
parler des dépenses communes
-Yeah. -...are gonna go to.
pour la maison.
And she's the bread winner at this point pretty much.
Elie gagne plus d'argent que moi.
And I think that is a source of insecurity for him as a man.
C‘est une source de mal—ètre pour lui.
RAJESH: Come on, you deserve one.
Tu la mérites.
You've worked hard to find a woman who makes a lot of money.
Tu as travaillé dur pour épouser une riche.
Then there's-- The upside is, "Oh, what's yours is mine.
On se dit: “Ce qui est a toi est a moi.
So I'm gonnajust go get this cool thing to make toys with whenever I want. "
Donc, je peux acheter ça pour faire des jouets."
Sorry, if you don't like it, but that's how love works.
Je suis désolé, mais l'amour, ça marche comme ça.
No. Here's how love works.
Non. Voilà comment ça marche.
You're gonna return the machine...
Tu vas la rapporter
...or you can print out a working set of lady parts and sleep with those.
ou tu peux t'imprimer une femme avec qui coucher.
Oh, my God, are you actually thinking about it?
Tu y penses vraiment ?
You know, it's a slow learning process for both of them.
C‘est un lent processus pour les deux.
Slower for him.
Plus pour lui.
[love you.
Je t‘aime.
I love you too. Sweet dreams. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
Moi aussi. Fais de beaux rêves. A demain.
Good night, rocket man.
Bonne nuit, capitaine.
To infinity and beyond, baby.
A toutjamais, chérie.
Something that I also find that's just so great about their relationship...
Je trouve aussi que les auteurs ont su
...and how the writers write them is you see the love between them...
montrer l‘amour qu'il y a entre eux.
...and I mean, the episode where Howard finds the letter from his father.
L‘épisode où Howard trouve la lettre de son père...
I read that episode, and was crying on my couch.
J'ai pleuré en lisant le script.
I just thought that was so beautifully written.
C‘était magnifique.
Why don't you read it?
Tu ne la lis pas ?
He abandoned me and my mother.
Il nous a abandonnés.
Why does he deserve a chance to explain anything?
Pourquoi mériterait-il de pouvoir s‘expliquer ?
So, what do you wanna do with it?
Que vas-tu faire ?
Something I should have done a long time ago.
Ce que j'aurais déjà dû faire il y a longtemps.
-Really? Are you sure? -Yup.
Tu es sûr ?
RAUCH: It's such a fantastic example of a true marriage.
C‘est un bel exemple du mariage.
He's going through it but bringing his wife along for the ride...
Il traverse une épreuve avec sa femme
...and she's as invested in the situation as he is.
et elle s'investit autant que lui.
Which again, I think it's very true to marriage...
C‘est ça le vrai mariage,
...that it's you and your spouse against the world.
vous et votre époux contre le reste du monde.
And I think that episode really exemplifies that.
Cet épisode l'illustre parfaitement.
This may be the potion talking, but you are one fine-ass dungeon master.
C‘est peut-être la potion qui te fait ça, mais tu es un grand maître.
Oh, yeah? Well, when we get home...
A la maison,
...l'm gonna take you on a whole different adventure.
je t‘emménerai dans une autre aventure.
I think everything in the show really does come back...
Tout dans la série revient
...to the love between these characters.
à l‘amour entre ces personnages.
Notjust us two, but all of us.
Pas juste nous.
And so you can have Bernadette scold Wolowitz...
Parfois, Bernadette Ie réprimande
...or Wolowitz act like a total buffoon.
ou il agit comme un débile.
[IMITATES RAJESH] Cinnamon, come to Daddy.
Cinnamon, Viens voir papa.
But it always just comes back to this sort of deep need for each other.
Mais on revient toujours a leur amour profond.
Thank you, guys.
Merci.
HELBERG: And I think that's one of the reasons...
C‘est pour ça que la série continue
...to do well and continue to create good stories...
à produire de belles histoires.
...is because all of these characters on the show need each other...
Tous les personnages dela série
...in some very real way.
ont besoin les uns des autres.
-Yeah, I agree. I agree with that. -lt's a testament to everybody...
- Je suis d‘accord. - Cela montre
...to just try to bring more and more truth to these characters.
que ces personnages sont de plus en plus vrais.
So, Alex, what's the topic of your dissertation?
Quel est le sujet de ta dissertation ?
I'm looking for Trojan asteroids at Earth's L5 Lagrange point.
Je cherche les astéroïdes troyens au point de Lagrange L5.
You two have a lot to talk about.
Vous avez beaucoup de choses a vous dire.
-Is he all right? -No.
- Il va bien ? - Non.
He can't talk to women.
Il ne parle pas aux nanas.
You're gonna have a very interesting relationship if you can't talk to them.
Ça donne des relations très intéressantes.
MAN 1: There's three cameras, yes. Is that your camera rolling there?
Il y a trois caméras. Ta caméra tourne la ?
MAN 2: Give me one second. MAN 1: Okay.
- Une seconde. - OK.
MAN 2: Three camera, common mark.
Trois caméras, clap.
There is nothing complacent about playing this character.
Jouer ce personnage n‘a rien de complaisant.
I don't know if I have the right answer.
J'ignore si j'ai la réponse.
"Relaxed" is a tough word to use...
”Détendu" est dur a utiliser
...because there's nothing really relaxed about him.
parce qu'il n‘est en rien détendu.
If you've been on a show for six years, you can't suspend time.
Impossible de suspendre le temps pendant six ans.
Characters are getting older. Their priorities have changed...
Les gens vieillissent. Leurs priorités dans la vie ont changé
...from sort of self-satisfaction to finding love or relationships.
de l'autosatisfaction a trouver l'amour.
You know, sort of moving forward and growing as people.
Ils évoluent et grandissent.
Hey, let's help Raj meet a girl tonight.
Aidons Raj à rencontrer une fille.
No, no, no. I'm fine.
Non, ça va.
By the way, are we talking one-night stand or do we wanna get him into a relationship?
Au fait, on parle de coup d'un soir ou de relation ?
Let's get him laid.
Trouvons-lui un coup.
NAYYAR: Raj got so desperate, I mean, to find someone.
Raj est si désespéré de trouver quelqu‘un.
You know, last season, he got set up on a blind date for marriage.
La saison dernière, il va a un rencard arrangé pour se marier.
And the woman ended up being a lesbian.
Et la fille est en fait lesbienne.
He fell in love with Siri, which is an iPhone-- The iPhone voice.
Il tombe amoureux de Siri, qui est la voix de l‘iPhone.
He got a puppy called Cinnamon Koothrappali.
Il prend un chiot appelé Cannelle Koothrappali.
He's trying everything to fill that void in his life.
Il essaie tout pour combler ce vide dans sa vie.
Bossa nova.
Bossa nova.
You listen to that with your hips as well as your ears.
Ça s'écoute avec les oreilles et les hanches.
Raj has become very good friends with Stuart in the comic book store.
Raj est devenu ami avec Stuart de la librairie de BD.
They're very lonely, and in their loneliness, they found each other.
Ils se sont trouvés dans leur solitude.
So you guys are, like, buds now?
Vous êtes potes maintenant ?
Oh, yeah. We hang out all the time.
On traîne tout le temps ensemble.
Plus, he doesn't have a girlfriend, I don't have a girlfriend.
Et il n‘a pas de petite amie, moi non plus.
It's like we both had these holes in our lives, but now we fill each other's holes.
On avait chacun ce trou dans nos vies et on remplit les trous de l'autre.
Stuart and him talk about comic books. They can talk about video games.
Stuart et lui parlent de BD, de jeux vidéo.
There's no social pressure to be on.
Sans pression sociale.
You and l have so much fun hanging out.
On s‘amuse bien. Si t‘étais une fille, nos problèmes seraient résolus.
NAYYAR: Short of actually wanting to make love to a man...
Si on écarte le fait de vouloir faire l‘amour a un homme...
-What? -...Raj really would love Stuart...
- Quoi ? - Raj adorerait
...to be his sort of life companion.
que Stuart soit son compagnon.
Cheers.
Santé.
He loves women. As you can tell in seasons leading up...
Il aime les femmes. Dans les autres saisons,
...he's always been-- He fancied himself when he's drunk a womanizer.
on voit que soûl, il rêve d‘être un don Juan.
And Raj is not shy to tell you what kind of women he likes, as we all know.
Et Raj ne manque pas de préciser quel type de femmes il aime.
They must be insanely hot.
Elles doivent être incroyablement sexy.
Like nines or tens.
Que des neuf ou des dix.
Nines or tens?
Des neuf ou des dix ?
Okay, an eight is acceptable...
Un huit est acceptable
...if she's willing to bring another eight to the hot tub.
si elle amène un autre huit dans le jacuzzi.
Bottom line, you'll take any woman who'll have you.
Tu prendras toute femme qui voudra de toi.
In a New Delhi minute.
Dans la minute.
He's just naive, which is really fun to play a character.
Il est naif, ce qui est amusant ajouer.
It's very freeing to play someone so naive.
C‘est libérateur de jouer quelqu'un de si naif.
Hey, Stuart, you got anything going on...
Stuart, tu as des plans
-...for Valentine's Day? -Not really.
- de St Valentin. - Pas vraiment.
Other than hiding all the sharp objects around here...
A part cacher les objets tranchants
...and white-knuckling it till morning. What do you got going on?
et serrer les dents jusqu'au lendemain. Et toi ?
Oh, well, I was gonna spend the night with my special little lady...
J'allais passer la nuit avec ma chérie,
...but she got worms and then I had to take her to the vet.
mais elle a chopé des vers etj'ai dû l‘emmener chez le véto.
On the Valentine's Day episode, Raj had nothing to do.
Dans l‘épisode dela St Valentin, Raj n‘avait rien a faire.
So he told Stuart, "Why don't we throw a Valentine's Day party...
Il dit a Stuart: ”Organisons une fête
...for the people who don't have anything to do on Valentine's Day."
pour ceux qui n‘ont rien a faire àla St Valentin."
And when the party starts, no one's having a good time.
Au début de la fête, personne ne s'amuse.
Everyone's feeling bummed about being lonely.
Tout le monde est déçu d‘être seul.
Then Raj gets up there and gives the speech of a lifetime...
Puis, Raj fait un discours spécial
...about, you know, "We're not pathetic people."
sur le sujet : ”on est pas pitoyables."
We are a community.
On est une communauté.
And as long as we have each other, we're never truly alone.
Si on est la les uns pour les autres, on n‘estjamais seuls.
NAYYAR: And after that speech, Lucy walks up to him and says:
Après ce discours, Lucy Vient le voir et dit:
That was cool, what you said.
C‘était cool, ce que tu as dit.
-You really think so? -Yeah, I do.
- Tu trouves ? - Oui.
And he basically is like, "Later, losers." He's, like, whatever and leaves.
Et en gros, quand il part, c‘est : "A plus, les losers".
But, you know, Lucy is interesting for Raj because he's finally met someone...
Lucy est intéressante, car Raj rencontre enfin quelqu'un
...who has more social anxiety than he does.
qui a plus de phobie sociale que lui.
I'm kind of broken.
Je suis un peu cassée.
That's great. I'm broken too.
C‘est super, moi aussi.
-Oh, no, you're not. -Oh, I totally am.
- Non. -Oh, si.
There are many things seriously wrong with me.
Il y a plein de choses qui clochent chez moi.
NAYYAR: And that, I think, puts him in a position...
Ce qui le met dans la position
...where he's the one taking care of someone...
de prendre soin de l‘autre
...and that helps him bring his guard down...
et ça l'aide à baisser sa garde.
...where he's not so self-conscious...
Il est moins complexé,
...because he's met someone who is, you know....
car il a rencontré quelqu'un qui...
She just has some more issues than he does.
Elle a plus de problèmes que lui et il la trouve trés séduisante.
Hey, Raj...
Sal ut, Raj.
...funny story.
Tu vas rire...
The first date, he thought the library would be the perfect spot...
Au premier rencard, il choisit la bibliothèque
...so he wouldn't be forced to talk to her without alcohol.
pour ne pas avoir a lui parler sans alcool.
RAJ ES H : As you're reading, it will help to remember...
Lire ceci t‘aidera a le souvenir
...I have an adorable accent.
que j'ai un accent adorable.
Raj is trying to find ways so that Lucy feels comfortable.
Raj essaie de mettre Lucy a l‘aise.
Confronting someone or pushing her boundaries.
En repoussant ses limites.
Maybe I could do one more scary thing before I go...
Je peux peut-être faire une dernière chose terrifiante
...and give you a kiss goodbye?
et t'embrasser ?
You know, if that's okay.
Si tu es d‘accord.
Panic attack. Maybe next time.
Panique. Peut-étre la prochaine fois.
I'm counting that as foreplay.
Je prends ça pour des préliminaires.
I think Lucy would make a great mate for him...
Lucy ferait une bonne partenaire pour lui
...because when he's in a position where he's taking control of the situation...
car il est en position de contrôler la situation.
...I feel like he puts that on the other person...
Il met ça sur le dos de l‘autre
...as opposed to himself, and that's a good relationship for him...
et c‘est une bonne relation pour lui,
...because A, he lets his guard down, which is very important.
car il baisse sa garde, ce qui est trés important.
And B, he feels like he's the one nurturing, you know...
Ensuite, il se sent comme un soutien,
...as opposed to being self-conscious about someone having to take care of him.
au lieu d‘être complexé qu'on doive s‘occuper de lui.
What's...? What is wrong with me?
Quel est mon probléme ?
Why can't I ever have love?
Pourquoi je ne peux pas avoir d‘amour ?
-You will. -No, l--
- Tu trouveras. - Non.
Well, I'm unlovable.
Je ne suis pas digne d'amour.
That's just the booze talking.
C‘est l'alcool qui parle.
I haven't had a drink since last night.
Je n'ai pas bu depuis hier soir.
-You're talking to me? -I am.
- Tu me parles ? - Oui.
And now I'm crying for a whole different reason.
Maintenant, je pleure pour autre chose.
ljust-- I want him to find love.
Je veux qu'il trouve l'amour.
I mean, everyone else has, and they've all deserved it.
Tout le monde l‘a fait et l‘a mérité.
I wanna see him succeed in whatever he does.
Je veux le voir réussir.
You know, I'd love to see him let his guard down and find love.
J'aimerais le voir baisser sa garde et trouver l'amour.